人人影視
YYeTs.com
原創翻譯  雙語字幕
■
本字幕由人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用作任何商業盈利行為
翻譯 Silmar
翻譯 送小孩
翻譯 小熊嘟嘟
翻譯 豬豬
翻譯 某羽 泰斯
繁化 Dien
校對 泰斯·雪諾
校對 Silmar
顧問 屈暢(ccxx)
時間軸 子衿
時間軸 Original
後期/特效 WiLL  吉吉
監製 泰斯·雪諾
改編自《冰與火之歌》
原著 喬治·R·R·馬丁
權力的遊戲
第三季 第九集
凱岩城
你有把握嗎
Are you sure about this?
沒有
No.
很危險
It's dangerous.
如果我們能奪下泰溫的居城
If we take Tywin's castle from him,
維斯特洛的領主們會明白他並非不可戰勝
the lords of Westeros will realize he's not invincible.
佔了他的老巢
Take his home,
搶了他的黃金  就奪走了他的權力
take his gold, take his power.
為什麼給我講這些
Why are you telling me?
您求我不要派席恩去和他父親談判
You begged me not to send Theon to negotiate with his father
我忽視了您的建議
and I ignored your advice.
如今臨冬城被焚為廢墟
Now Winterfell is burnt to the ground,
北境遭鐵種荼毒
the North is overrun with ironborn,
布蘭和瑞肯也不在了
and Bran and Rickon are gone.
所以關於凱岩城
So Casterly Rock...
我在問您的意見
I'm asking your advice.
我們兵力夠嗎
We have enough men?
如果瓦德·佛雷肯合作
If Walder Frey cooperates.
如果我們拿下城堡之前
If reinforcements arrive from King's Landing
君臨援軍趕到
before we take the castle...
我們會被夾在泰溫的大軍和大海之間
we'll be caught between Tywin's army and the sea.
我們會輸掉戰爭  像父親一樣死去
We'll lose the war and die the way Father died.
或者更糟
Or worse.
讓他們嘗嘗痛失所愛的滋味
Show them how it feels to lose what they love.
諸位貴賓
My honored guests...
我的居所歡迎你們
be welcome within my walls
我的餐桌招待你們
and at my table.
你們將得到我的款待
I extend to you my hospitality
和七神之光的保護
and protection in the light of the Seven.
感謝您的盛情  大人
We thank you for your hospitality, my lord.
大人  我特來向您致歉
I have come to make my apologies, my lord,
求您原諒
and to beg your forgiveness.
不要求我原諒  陛下
Don't beg my forgiveness, Your Grace.
被你拋棄的不是我  而是我家的女孩們
It wasn't me you spurned. It was my girls.
她們之中本該有人成為王后
One of them was supposed to be queen.
如今卻沒人戴上后冠
Now none of them are.
這是我女兒艾雯
This is Arwyen my daughter.
我女兒瓦妲  女兒德瓦
My daughter Walda, my daughter Derwa,
女兒瓦拉
my daughter Waldra.
我的長孫女
My eldest granddaughters
吉娜和內拉
Ginia and Neila.
雙胞胎孫女  西拉和撒拉
Serra and Sarra, granddaughters, twins.
原本你要哪個都可以
You could have had either.
兩個都要我也不在乎
Could have had both for all I care.
孫女瑪麗安
My granddaughter Marianne.
孫女佛雷亞
My granddaughter Freya.
孫女...
My granddaughter...
維瑟
Wertha.
瓦拉
Waldra.
瓦迪娜
Waldina.
-我是梅裡  -好吧
- I'm Merry. - Fine.
還有我最小的女兒希琳
And here's my youngest daughter Shirei,
不過她還沒來月事
though she hasn't bled yet.
顯然你也沒耐心等
Clearly you don't have the patience for all that.
小姐們
My ladies.
男人應當言而有信  人君更當如此
All men should keep their word, kings most of all.
我立約迎娶你們中的一位  卻違背了誓言
I was pledged to marry one of you and I broke that vow.
錯在我  不在你們
The fault is not with you.
任何有幸迎娶你們的人都當倍感幸運
Any man would be lucky to have any one of you.
我所為並非輕賤諸位
I did what I did not to slight you,
只因我心另有所屬
but because I loved another.
我知道略略數語不足以彌補
I know these words cannot set right
我對你們和貴家族犯下的過失
the wrong I have done to you and your house.
我請求你們原諒
I beg your forgiveness
我願盡我所能做出補償
and pledge to do all I can to make amends
以求渡口的佛雷家和臨冬城的史塔克家
so the Freys of the Crossing and the Starks of Winterfell
能夠重歸於好
may once again be friends.
很好
Very good.
她在這裡呢
There she is.
走近些
Come closer.
讓我好好看看你
Let me have a look at you.
還是看不清
Still can't see you.
老眼昏花啊
Old eyes.
真愛
Love.
臨冬城的史塔克家是這樣說的嗎
That's what the Starks of Winterfell call it, eh?
真是高尚
Very honorable.
我說就是臉蛋漂亮
I call it a pretty face.
真是美人
Mmm, very pretty.
當然比這群貨色強多了
Prettier than this lot, that's for sure.
身材也好
Very shapely as well.
想用這身裙子藏住她嗎
Oh, you try to hide her under that dress.
要是想藏著她
If you wanted to hide her,
就不該帶她過來
you shouldn't have brought her here in the first place.
裙子下面的動靜
I can always see
我總能一目瞭然
what's going on beneath a dress.
經驗太豐富了
Been at this a long time.
我敢說你脫掉那裙子之後
I bet when you take that dress off,
裡面的東西分毫不動
everything stays right where it is.
一寸都不會下垂
Doesn't drop an inch.
你的國王說他背叛我是為了真愛
Your king says he betrayed me for love.
我說他是為了堅實的奶子
I say he betrayed me for firm tits
和緊實的小洞
and a tight fit.
這種行為我可以尊重
And I can respect that.
我在你這年紀  肯為她違背五十個誓言
When I was your age, I'd have broken 50 oaths
眼都不眨一下
to get into that without a second thought.
我家大廳容得下在場的各位
Well, I've enough room in the hall for you lot.
至於其他人等
We'll set up tents outside
外面自有帳篷  食物和麥酒提供
with food and ale for the rest of your men.
多謝  大人
Thank you, my lord.
開始準備吧
Well, let's get ready.
美酒滿堂紅
The wine will flow red
琴瑟震耳聾
and the music will play loud
這事兒就過去了
and we'll put this mess behind us.
哪裡
Where?
這裡
There.
這裡  是後門
There. It's a back gate.
我的手下穿過這道門找淵凱的床奴
My men use it when they visit Yunkai's bed slaves.
你的手下  你沒去嗎
Your men, but not you?
我對奴隸不感興趣
I have no interest in slaves.
人豈能與財物交歡
A man cannot make love to property.
我們從這裡進城
This is where we enter the city.
守衛很少  他們認識我
Very few guards. They know me.
他們會讓我進去
They let me inside--
一整支軍隊不可能摸進後門
We're not gonna sneak an army through a back gate.
我殺守衛  帶您麾下的兩名好手
I kill the guards. I take your two best men
穿過街巷  路線我自是瞭如指掌
and lead them through the back streets, which I know well,
然後打開正門
and open the front gates.
讓軍隊進城
Then comes the army.
城門一旦突破  幾個小時便能得手
Once the walls are breached, the city will fall in hours.
或者你帶領灰蟲子和我走上死路
Or perhaps you'll lead Grey Worm and me to the slaughter,
除掉我軍的將領
cutting the head off our army.
淵凱的賢主大人會付你酬金
The masters of Yunkai will pay you your fee
你也不必一分為三
and you won't have to split it three ways
因為你已經殺了同伴
'cause you've already slaughtered your partners.
你疑心過重
You have a very suspicious mind.
據我的經驗  只有不誠實的人才會如此
In my experience, only dishonest people think this way.
你指揮無垢者
You command the Unsullied.
你怎麼看
What do you think?
你現在是首領
你相信他嗎
我相信他
你們今晚動身
You leave tonight.
很好
Very good.
我們去準備
We'll prepare.
喬拉爵士
Ser Jorah.
我也能出一份力
You can use an extra sword.
你是女王鐵衛  巴利斯坦爵士
You're the Queensguard, Ser Barristan.
你理應守在女王左右
Your place is by the queen.
如果我們真是她忠誠的僕從
If we are truly her loyal servants,
那就要盡應盡的本分
we'll do whatever needs to be done
不計代價  無所謂尊嚴
no matter the cost, no matter our pride.
我們在黑城堡以西
We're west of Castle Black,
但長夜堡離我們更近
but the Nightfort's closest to us.
它是長城上第一座城堡
It was the first castle on the Wall.
傑赫里斯一世國王統治時  守夜人棄守此處
The Watch abandoned it during the reign of King Jaehaerys I.
城堡太大  無法維持
Too big. Impossible to maintain.
除了黑城堡
Other than Castle Black itself,
我們也能走長夜堡
the Nightfort's the perfect castle for us.
那裡有道暗門
It's got a secret sally port,
名叫黑門  跟長城一樣古老
the Black Gate, as old as the Wall itself.
恐怕幾百年都沒人用過了
No one's used it in centuries most likely.
密道橫穿長城
It leads through the Wall
直抵長夜堡
right down into the Nightfort,
這門不好找
if one knows how to find it,
不過我恰好知道在哪裡
which, it just so happens, I do.
你怎麼會知道這些事
How do you know all that?
我在一本很古老的書中讀過
I read about it in a very old book.
光靠盯著紙上的符號  就知道這麼多
You know all that from staring at marks on paper?
是的
Yes.
你像個魔法師
You're like a wizard.
我們的父親以前總說
Our father used to tell us
沒有野人能活著看到長城
that no wildling ever looked upon the Wall and lived.
我們看到了
Here we are.
而且還活著
Alive.
記住逃跑的小孩是什麼下場
Remember what happens to children who run.
我現在是你父親  我來說話
I'm your father and I'll do the talking.
路況真是糟透了  不是嗎
The roads have gone right to hell, haven't they?
今早就斷了三根輪軸
Cracked three spokes this morning.
-要搭把手嗎  -八把手才夠
- Need a hand? - Need about eight hands.
婚禮前必須把醃豬肉
Got to get this salt pork to the Twins
送到孿河城
in time for the wedding.
非常感謝
Many thanks.
不要
Don't!
別殺他
Don't kill him.
死耗子不會叫
Dead rats don't squeak.
你可真是危險人物啊
You're so dangerous, aren't you?
嚇唬小女孩
Saying scary things to little girls.
殺害小孩子和老人
Killing little boys and old people.
好一條鐵血硬漢
A real hard man you are.
你認識的人都比不過
More than anyone you know.
你錯了  我認識一個殺手
You're wrong. I know a killer.
-一個真正的殺手  -是嗎
- A real killer. - That so?
你在他面前就是隻小貓
You'd be like a kitten to him.
他用小拇指就能幹掉你
He'd kill you with his little finger.
就是他嗎
That him?
-不是  -很好
- No. - Good.
別殺他
Don't kill him.
求你了
Please.
求你別殺他
Please don't.
你很善良
You're very kind.
早晚會被自己的善心害死
Someday it'll get you killed.
這是哪裡
Where are we?
應該是贈地
The Gift, I think.
築城者布蘭登將長城以南的這片土地
Brandon the Builder gave all this land
全部送給黑衣弟兄
south of the Wall to the Night's Watch
以供他們維持生計
for their sustenance and support.
魯溫學士告訴我的
Maester Luwin taught me that.
現在好像沒什麼人了
Doesn't seem to be supporting anyone at the moment.
多好的地方  又沒有戰爭
It's good land and there's no war up here.
人們為什麼離開呢
Why leave?
因為野人
Wildlings.
對不起
Sorry.
他們越過長城  擄掠偷盜
But they come over the Wall and raid,
搶走女人
steal, carry off women.
老奶媽說  他們用你的頭骨做杯子
Old Nan said they turn your skull into a cup
讓你用骨頭杯子喝自己的血
and make you drink your own blood from it.
老奶媽這麼說的
That's what Old Nan said.
暴風雨要來了
There's a storm coming.
我怎麼沒看見
I don't see any.
這地方躲雨再好不過了
It's as good a place to shelter as any.
我們可以邊等邊喝點血
We can drink some blood while we wait.
我喝的不多
I don't need much.
只有一個老頭  還有八匹好馬
Only one old man and eight good horses.
一個老頭要八匹馬幹什麼
What's one old man doing with eight horses?
為守夜人養的
He breeds them for the Watch.
那他怎麼防人家偷馬
How's he keep folks from stealing them?
守夜人保護他
The Watch protects him.
今天可沒人保護
Not today they don't.
賣馬的屋裡肯定有金子
He's selling horses, he's got some gold in there.
-和上好的鐵器  -走  把他給撂了
- And proper steel. - Let's carve him up.
我們搶了馬就走
We just take the horses and go.
這老頭沒有威脅
The old man's no threat.
我說得沒錯吧
I keep telling you.
他已經老了
He's an old man.
這會兒我們一矛捅了他
A spear through the heart's a better way to die
總比只有幾匹馬聽著他咳死來得好
than coughing up your last with no one but your horses to hear.
對付偷馬賊  守夜人可能派幾個人找找了事
The Watch might send a few men looking for a horse thief.
對付殺人犯  他們肯定會大動干戈
They'll send a lot more to hunt down murderers.
正合我意
I hope so.
在城堡裡殺守夜人難
Killing crows in their castle is tough.
但在野外殺他們
Killing them out here in the open,
是我們的拿手好戲
that's what we do.
散開
Spread out.
包圍前進
Surround the hut and move in.
耶哥蕊特
Ygritte!
把穀倉給我清了
Clear the barn!
你把豬都吃了  誰相信你是豬倌
No one's going to believe you're a hog farmer if you eat them all.
豬身上最好的部位
Best part of the animal.
別著急  他們還在那裡
Don't worry. They're still there.
我知道他們沒走
I know they're still there.
你一會兒看一次
You check every five minutes
像是怕他們跑了似的
like you're afraid they're gonna move.
我不怕
I'm not afraid.
你當然怕
Of course you are.
你現在快到了
You're almost there
害怕到頭來一場空
and you're afraid you won't make it.
離得越近  你越是害怕
The closer you get, the worse the fear gets.
掩飾是沒有用的
No point in trying to hide behind that face.
我一眼就能看出恐懼
I know fear when I see it.
見得多了
Seen it a lot.
我一眼就能看出你怕
I knew fear when I saw it in you.
你害怕火
You're afraid of fire.
貝里的劍一著火
When Beric's sword went up in flames,
你就嚇得跟個小丫頭似的
you looked like a scared little girl.
而且我知道你為什麼怕
And I know why, too.
我聽說過你哥哥對你做的事
I heard what your brother did to you.
把你的臉按到火堆裡
Pressed your face to the fire
當作肉排給烤了
like you're a nice juicy mutton chop.
受到啟發了不成
That give you some ideas?
有可能
Might do.
那就來吧
Go ahead, then.
說不定能逃走
You might get away.
說不定還能自己找到地方
Might even make it there on your own.
他們就在河對面
They're just over the river.
你老爹被伊林·派恩砍腦袋之後
The closest you've been to family
這是你離家人最近的一次
since Ilyn Payne snipped your daddy's neck.
總有一天我要一劍刺進你眼睛
Someday I'm gonna put a sword through your eye
從後腦勺穿出來
and out the back of your skull.
怎麼才能翻過長城呢
How are we going to get past the Wall?
我叔叔說有七百英呎高
My uncle said it's 700 feet high.
你是怎麼過來的
How did you get past it?
坐船走海豹灣
Got in a boat and rowed past the Bay of Seals.
從這裡到海豹灣要走兩個月
It would take us two months to get to the Bay of Seals.
有的直接從冰牆上爬過去
Some climb straight up the ice.
阿多那麼強壯
Even Hodor's not strong
背著我也爬不過去
enough to climb the Wall with me on his back.
阿多
Hodor.
鎮守長城的有十九座城堡
19 castles guard the Wall.
-只剩三座有人駐守  -阿多
- Only three are still manned. - Hodor!
可以找一座廢棄的穿過去
One of those abandoned fortresses will give us a way through.
我叔叔說城堡廢棄時
My uncle said the gates were sealed with ice and stone
會用冰和石頭封門
when the castles were deserted.
那我們就再打開
Well, we'll have to open them up again.
外面有個騎兵
There's a rider out there.
就一個嗎
Just one?
-不止一個  -阿多
- There's more. - Hodor!
-不過是打雷而已  大塊頭  -阿多
- It's just thunder, sweet giant. - Hodor.
我投降
I yield.
-我投降  -是野人
- I yield. - Wildlings.
毛毛狗和夏天呢
Where's Shaggydog and Summer?
捕獵去了
Hunting.
阿多
Hodor!
-安靜  阿多  -阿多
- Quiet, Hodor. - Hodor!
讓他閉嘴  要是他們聽到...
Make him shut up. If they hear us...
-噓  阿多  別喊阿多了  -阿多
- Hush, Hodor. No more Hodoring. - Hodor!
-阿多  -阿多  鎮定點
- Hodor! - Hodor, calm down.
-你要保持安靜  -他們會聽到的
- You need to keep quiet. - They're gonna hear us.
阿多  安靜
Hodor, be quiet.
-阿多  -阿多  鎮定
- Ah! Hodor! - Hodor, calm down.
-阿多  阿多  -阿多  安靜
- Hodor! Hodor! - Hodor, be quiet!
你做了什麼
What did you do?
什麼都沒做
Nothing.
我不知道
I don't know.
怎麼回事
What's that?
有匹馬快死了
That's a horse dying.
把馬帶過來
Bring them over here.
這是最後一匹  其他的都死了
That was the last of them. The rest are dead.
我聽見上面有喊叫聲
I heard shouting up there.
雷聲
Thunder.
我分得出雷聲和叫聲
I know the difference between shouting and thunder.
也許是鬼
Maybe it's ghosts.
這是自討苦吃  老爹
That won't help you, grandpa.
你要騎到哪裡去
Where you riding?
現在說這些還有用嗎
Doesn't matter now, does it?
是啊  沒用了
No, it doesn't matter now.
割了他的喉嚨  否則他會告訴烏鴉我們來了
Cut his throat or he'll tell the crows we're here.
你明白的
You understand.
至少讓我站起來
Let me stand at least.
讓我死得有點尊嚴
Let me go with a bit of dignity.
讓那烏鴉動手
Make the crow kill him.
你現在是我們的人  證明看看
You're one of us now. Prove it.
狼就在外面
The wolves are out there.
我不能主動控制
I can't do it by choice.
我不知道該怎麼做  是夢裡發生的
I don't know how. It happens in my dreams.
你是狼靈  布蘭
You're a warg, Bran.
這存在於你的血脈中
It's in your blood.
我做不到
I can't.
你剛才對他做過了
You just did with him.
一頭狼根本算不了什麼
A wolf is nothing compared to that.
看起來挺鋒利
She looks sharp.
動手
Do it.
我早說了  他還是烏鴉
I told you. He's still one of them.
動手啊  小子
Go on, boy.
動手
Go on!
他是烏鴉
He's a crow.
永遠都是烏鴉
He'll always be a crow.
瞧他那烏鴉婆娘護著他呢
And here's his crow wife guarding him.
一有機會  他就會背後捅我們刀子
He'll stab us in the back first chance he gets.
殺了他
Kill him.
-他還是他們的人  -不
- He's one of them. - No!
聽到了嗎
Do you hear me?
你不能為他們的人送死
You're not gonna die for one of them.
快做
Do it.
否則他們會發現我們
They'll find us if you don't.
你一直都是對的
You were right the whole time.
聽到我吹的鳥叫聲  你們就上
When you hear a songbird's whistle, you come.
我吹得可棒了  世上沒人比得過我
I'm a great whistler. The greatest in the land.
達里奧·納哈里斯
Daario Naharis.
這傢伙身手挺快
That one was quick.
-可能還有別人  -不會的
- There may be others. - I doubt it.
淵凱人更願意讓奴隸出戰
The Yunkish prefer to let their slaves do their fighting for them.
你管這叫守衛很少
That's what you call a few guards?
來啊  看你還有什麼招數
Come on! What do you got, huh?
艾德慕大人
Lord Edmure...
希望我沒讓您失望
I hope I'm not a disappointment to you.
您讓我喜不自勝  小姐
You're a delight to me, my lady.
請給新娘披上斗篷
You may now cloak the bride
象徵永久的守護
and bring her under your protection.
在七神的見證下
In the sight of the Seven,
兩個靈魂合二為一
I hereby seal these two souls,
永結連理
binding them as one for eternity.
請兩位對視  朗誦誓詞
Look upon each other and say the words.
天父  鐵匠  戰士  聖母
Father, Smith, warrior, Mother,
少女  老嫗  陌客
Maiden, Crone, Stranger...
-我屬於她  -我屬於他
- I am hers... - I am his...
-她屬於我  -他屬於我
- and she is mine... - and he is mine...
從今日起  至死方休
...from this day until the end of my days.
-這樣沒事嗎  -他們都走遠了
- Is that safe? - They're long gone.
你是對的
You were right.
我能隨時進入夏天的意識
I can get inside Summer's mind whenever I want.
這是當然
Of course you can.
長城以北有些野人
North of the Wall there are wildlings
可以控制各種各樣的動物
who can control all sorts of animals.
但你做的遠不止如此
But you did a lot more than that.
你進入了阿多的意識
You got inside Hodor's mind.
長城以北的人做不到嗎
They can't do that north of the Wall?
無論哪裡  都沒人能做到
No one can do that... anywhere.
我用夏天的眼睛看時
When I was looking through Summer's eyes,
-看見了瓊恩  -他在哪裡
- I saw Jon. - Where?
他跟野人在一起
He was with the wildlings.
他們想殺他  但他逃走了
They tried to kill him, but he got away.
那他肯定是回黑城堡去了
He'll be heading back to Castle Black, then.
我們該去那裡
That's where we should go.
就我們所知  黑城堡已經遭到攻擊
For all we know, Castle Black's already under attack.
-如果這麼多野人過了...  -我說過
- If this many wildlings got through-- - I already told you.
我不去長城以北
I'm not going north of the Wall.
玖健說的都是真的
Everything Jojen told me is true.
你看見我對阿多做的事了
You saw what I did to Hodor.
我必須找到三眼烏鴉
I have to find the three-eyed raven.
聽我說  小少爺
Listen to me, little lord.
別擔心
Don't worry.
我沒要你跟我去
I'm not asking you to come with me.
那對瑞肯也不安全
It won't be safe for Rickon.
我  我要跟你走
Me? I'm coming with you.
不
No.
你  歐莎和毛毛狗去最後壁爐城
You and Osha and Shaggydog head for the Last Hearth.
安柏家是我們的封臣  他們會保護你
The Umbers are our bannermen. They'll protect you.
我要跟你走
I'm coming with you.
我是你弟弟
I'm your brother.
我必須保護你
I have to protect you.
現在是我必須保護你
Right now I have to protect you.
羅柏在打仗  我要去長城之外
Robb's at war and I'm going beyond the Wall.
如果我們出了什麼事
If something happens to us,
你就是臨冬城的繼承人
you're the heir to Winterfell.
你知道怎麼找到最後壁爐城嗎
Would you know how to find the Last Hearth?
你們南方佬建了大城堡就不挪腳了
You southerners build your big castles and you never move.
好找得很
You're easy to find.
我們不是南方佬
We're not southerners.
我不想離開你
And I don't want to leave you.
過來  小戰士
Come here, little soldier.
我們兩個要去探險了
You and me, we're gonna have some adventures.
你不必做這些的
You don't have to do any of this.
你家人收留了我
Your family took me in
毫無理由地對我好
and was good to me when they had no cause to be.
我們兩個沒事的
We'll be fine, you and me.
安柏家的人都是偉大的戰士
The Umbers are great warriors.
連我都是聽著他們的故事長大的
Even I heard about them growing up.
他們會教你怎麼使劍
They'll teach you how to swing a sword.
我知道怎麼使劍
I know how to swing a sword.
你們這就要走嗎  現在可是半夜
You're leaving now? It's the middle of the night.
我學過怎樣在黑暗裡行走
I learned to walk in darkness.
說再見吧  小伙子
Say your good-byes, little man.
保護好這傢伙
Keep this one safe.
他是我最重要的人
He means the world to me.
我們已經等了很久
We've been waiting a long time.
不是嗎
Haven't we?
我不知道  告訴我
I don't know, you tell me.
攻陷一座城要多久
How long does it take to sack a city?
一切如您所說
It was just as you said.
他們不到最後關頭都不相信
They did not believe until it was too late.
他們的奴隸士兵
Their slave soldiers
丟下長矛  投降了
threw down their spears and surrendered.
達里奧·納哈里斯呢
And Daario Naharis?
城是您的了  我的女王
The city is yours, my queen.
樂師不錯
They're good, aren't they?
花了大價錢  他們當然要賣力
They ought to be because they cost enough.
看那幫傢伙
Look at the crowd there.
從奔流城過來的一路上
He complained about this marriage
他都在抱怨這樁婚事
the entire ride from Riverrun,
現在你看看他
and now look at him.
諸神就愛獎賞傻瓜
The gods love to reward a fool.
-叔叔  -怎麼了
- Uncle. - What?
他是我侄子  我愛他
He's my nephew. I love him.
不過他是個純粹的傻瓜
And he's a damned fool.
你不喝酒嗎  波頓大人
Don't you drink, Lord Bolton?
從不喝酒  夫人  酒讓人遲鈍
Never do, my lady. Dulls the senses.
確實如此
That's the point.
你娶過佛雷家的女孩吧
Didn't you marry one of these Frey girls?
對
Aye.
瓦德大人讓我從他孫女裡隨便挑
Lord Walder let me choose any of his granddaughters
還允諾以新娘等體重的銀子做嫁妝
and promised me the girl's weight in silver as a dowry.
所以我娶了個年輕的胖新娘
So I have a fat young bride.
但願她讓你非常幸福
I hope she makes you very happy.
她讓我非常富有
Well, she's made me very rich.
抱歉  大人  夫人
Pardon, my lord, my lady.
我要去找棵樹撒泡尿
I need to find a tree to piss on.
我母親跟盧斯·波頓獨處了
My mother's alone with Roose Bolton.
我該去救她
I should rescue her.
我見過所有女人裡
Your mother is less in need of rescue
你母親最不需要救了
than any woman I've ever met.
積點口德
Be kind.
她好不容易才開始喜歡你
She's finally starting to like you.
我也喜歡她
And I like her.
可是如果一切如她所願
But if she had her way,
我就回瓦蘭提斯彈我的豎琴去了
I would be back in Volantis playing my harp
而你會坐在那裡
and you would be sitting over there
被蘿絲琳餵黑莓
eating blackberries out of Roslin Frey's hand.
也許我犯了個大錯
Perhaps I've made a terrible mistake.
打國王可是叛國行為
Striking your king is an act of treason.
不  不要
No, don't.
不要羞辱他們
Don't insult them.
陛下
Your Grace.
修士的虔誠話也說過啦
The septon has prayed his prayers,
諾言也許下啦
some words were said,
艾德慕大人
and Lord Edmure
用他的斗篷裹走了我女兒
has wrapped my daughter in a cloak.
可他們還不是夫妻哩
But they are not yet man and wife.
寶劍配好鞘
A sword needs a sheath.
婚禮入洞房
And a wedding needs a bedding.
陛下您怎麼說
What does my sire say?
上床  上床  鬧洞房
To bed! To bed! To bed!
如果你認為是時候了  瓦德大人
If you think the time is right, Lord Walder,
就開始吧
by all means, let us bed them.
上床  上床  鬧洞房
To bed! To bed! To bed!
快點
Go on!
小心點  小姐們
Oh! Careful now, ladies.
野獸一旦放出來
Once you set that monster free,
就關不回去了
there's no caging him again.
上床  上床  鬧洞房
To bed! To bed! To bed!
可憐的姑娘
Poor girl.
每個新娘都要經這麼一遭
Every bride suffers the same.
我相信您優雅地忍耐了
I'm sure you endured yours with grace.
奈德沒讓鬧
Oh, Ned forbade it.
他說在新婚之夜
He said it wouldn't be right
打斷人家下巴很不合適
if he broke a man's jaw on our wedding night.
真是奇怪的風俗
That is a very strange custom.
在外鄉人看來
I suppose it does seem strange
的確是很奇怪
from a foreigner's perspective.
你覺得正常嗎
It seems normal to you?
只是傳統
It's a tradition.
不鬧新房的話  就不能證明
Without the bedding ceremony, there's no real proof
領主和夫人正式圓房
the lord and lady consummated their marriage.
有其他方式能證明
But there are other ways of providing proof.
男孩還是女孩
Boy or girl?
我不知道
I don't know.
如果是男孩  我知道該起什麼名字
But if it's a boy, I know what we should name him.
是嗎
Oh, do you?
取名字的
It seems to me the father
好像應該是父親的事吧
should have some say in his son's naming.
艾德
Eddard.
你不想教小奈德·史塔克
Don't you want to teach little Ned Stark
如何騎馬嗎
how to ride horses?
我想
I do.
快  列隊
Go on, line 'em up!
你做什麼
Where are you going?
給婚宴送鹹肉
Got salt pork for the feast.
宴會結束了
The feast is over.
聽起來不像結束了
Doesn't sound like it's over.
我跟你說結束了  就是結束了
If I tell you it's over, it's over.
調轉車頭  給我滾遠點
Turn this cart around and get the hell out of here.
還有醃豬蹄
Got pig's feet, too.
你腦子有病嗎
Are you soft in the head?
調轉車頭
Turn this cart around.
陛下
Your Grace.
我的招待怕是
I feel I've been remiss
有所怠慢
in my duties.
我奉送了酒肉和音樂
I've given you meat and wine and music,
但還沒有
but I haven't shown you
給您應有的款待
the hospitality you deserve.
國王已完婚
My king has married
我欠新王后一份禮
and I owe my new queen a wedding gift.
羅柏
Robb!
你們準備回臨冬城了嗎
You ready to head home to Winterfell, right?
宴會結束了  是嗎
Feast over yet, is it?
是  結束了
Aye, it's over.
跟著他
Follow him.
瞄準
Aim!
太遲了
It's too late.
北境之王起立了哩
The King in the North arises.
瓦德大人
Lord Walder!
瓦德大人  夠了
Lord Walder, enough!
收手吧
Let it end!
求您了
Please.
他是我兒子
He is my son.
我頭一個兒子
My first son.
放他走  我發誓我們絕不記恨
Let him go and I swear that we will forget this.
我向新舊諸神發誓
I swear it by the old gods and new.
我們絕不會復仇
We will take no vengeance.
你曾在我的城堡  就在這裡對我發過誓
You already swore me one oath right here in my castle.
你向諸神發誓你兒子會娶我女兒
You swore by all the gods your son would marry my daughter!
留我當人質吧  放羅柏走
Take me for a hostage, but let Robb go.
羅柏  站起來
Robb, get up.
站起來  快走
Get up and walk out.
求求你
Please!
我憑什麼放他走
And why would I let him do that?
以我身為徒利家人的榮譽
On my honor as a Tully,
以我身為史塔克家人的榮譽
on my honor as a Stark,
放他走
let him go
不然我就割了你妻子的喉嚨
or I will cut your wife's throat.
那我再娶一個
I'll find another.
母親
Mother.
蘭尼斯特家向您致以親切問候
The Lannisters send their regards.